MD. MAHID CHOUDHURY

Mailing Address: Permanent Address:

143/3 J.N Shaha Road, #Vill : Shimulia , #P.0 : Holodia, Lalbagh, Dhaka-1211 #U.P: Louhajang, #Dist : Munshiganj

E-mail: mahid.cse@gmail.com
Web: http://mahidcse.github.io/

Ph: 01911191597

Career Objective:

To build up a perfect career where I can put my maximum effort, academic knowledge and experience in a reputed organization where quality, performance, sincerity and activity is recognized and where I will totally able to prove myself.

Technical Skill:

- -Programming Skills: Asp.Net(C#), C, C++, PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3
- Mobile Development: Android Application Development
- Asp.Net Frameworks: Asp.Net MVC 5, Entity Framework (Razor, LINQ, Lambda Expressions)
- PHP Frameworks: CodeIgniterCSS Frameworks: Bootstrap
- JS Framework: JQuery, Angular JsDatabase: MySQL, MS SQL Server
- Web Servers: Apache, IIS, Wamp, Xamp
- CMS: Wordpress, Wordpress Theme Development, Opencart
- Software Development: Agile Methodology
- Operating Systems: Windows XP/7/Vista/8, Linux-Ubuntu/Red Hat/Fedora, Android
- Applications: Visual Studio, Git, Eclipse, Notepad++, Netbeans, Dreamweaver, emacs, MS Office
- Graphics: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

Academic Qualification:

■ M.Sc. in Computer Science & Engineering

Name of University: Jahangirnagar University

Major : Computer Programming & Software Engineering

Passing Year : 2017 Result : Applied

■ Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

Name of University: Institute of Science & Technology (National University)

Major : Computer Programming & Software Engineering

Passing Year : 2012 Result : First Division

■ Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C)

Name of College : Ideal College
Board : Dhaka
Major : Science
Year of Passing : 2007

Result : A

■ Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C)

Name of School : Brahman Gaon High School

Board : Dhaka
Major : Science
Year of Passing : 2005
Result : A



Job Experience:

Domain Software Technology

Job Title : Senior Software Engineer. Duration : February, 2017 to Till Now.

Domain Software Technology

Job Title : Software Engineer.

Duration: February, 2016 to 31 January, 2017.

⇒ National Television Limited (Rtv)

Job Title: Web Developer.

Duration: February, 2015 to 31 January, 2016

Essence Tech Solution

Job Title: Web Developer.

Duration: April, 2014 to January, 2015

Training & Achievements:

- → Participated in Asp.Net training BASIS-BITM.
- Participated in National Hackathon 2015.
- Participated in Code Warriors Challenge 2015.
- → Participated in Dynamic Web Development with PHP and MySQL course at Institute of Science and Technology.
- → Participated in "Programming Contest 2011" at Institute of Science and Technology. Our team "Epsilon Closure" achieved fourth position among 12 teams.

Language:

- Bengali: Proficient in writing, reading and speaking (Native).
- English: Proficient in writing, reading and speaking.

Interest and Hobbies:

⇒ Programming, Internet browsing, Music, Traveling, Reading Science Fiction Books, Reading Newspaper. Playing Badminton, Solving Rubik's cube

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Ruhul Amin Choudhury

Mother's Name : Mabiya Akhter Date of Birth : 12-12-1990

Religion : Islam

Nationality : Bangladeshi (by birth)

Marital Status : Single Sex : Male Blood Group : O+

Reference:

Md. Abdul Mazid

Associate Professor & Deputy Director Institute of Science and Technology

Ph: 01922526320

E-mail: mamazid@istbd.org

Signature & Date:

(Md. Mahid Choudhury)